<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<title>Guara Overview</title>
		<author email="leandro@ibnetwork.com.br">Leandro Rodrigo Saad Cruz</author>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<section name="Latest Changes (since Mar/2006)">
			<p>
				<ul>
					<li><b>11/Jun/2006</b> (guara-0.7.5 on svn TRUNK)</li>
					<li>Moved guara source tree to svn</li>
					<li><b>May/2006</b></li>
					<li>replaced JCL by SLF4J</li>
					<li>Added template mapping (like struts) to determine which template should be rendered after controller/action execution</li>
					<li>Moved Factory component to xingu-creator</li>
					<li><b>04/Mar/2006</b> (guara-0.7.3 on cvs HEAD)</li>
					<li>Changed module <a href="module-outcome.html">Outcome</a> code to String</li>
					<li>Mapping methods on Outcomes</li>
					<li>Exporting mock classes as part of the public API</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		</section>
		<section name="Overview">
      		<p>
				Guara is a <b>really simple and small</b> web application framework, 
				with a minimum set of dependencies that should serve 
				as a base to build other frameworks. <br/>
				Today we provide a basic configuration that resembles 
				<a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/turbine/fsd.html">Turbine Functional Specification</a> 
				were applications are composed of modules (Actions and Screens)
				performing business and presentation logic
				and different template types (Layouts,Navigations and Screens) 
				that are glued together by a template engine.
			</p>
			<subsection name="Motivation">
				<p>
					Guara was inspired by <a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/turbine/">Turbine's</a>
					accomplishments and mistakes. <br/>
					One of the things that we <b>really</b> like about Turbine is the ability to build
					the page from different chunks (templates) of data, promoting greater code reuse 
					at the template level. <br/>
					Some of the the many things we don't like about Turbine are :
					<ul>
						<li>Turbine is too big: this is a problem with lots of web frameworks I have seem</li>
						<li>Turbine is both a framework and a set off components/services put together</li>
						<li>Most of the Turbine components are tied to the framework some how</li>
						<li>Turbine enforces a particular workflow to serve the user request. <a href="#">Read more</a></li>
						<li>Turbine page generation is complicated and difficult to customize or extend</li>
						<li>Turbine removed support for <a href="http://freemarker.sourceforge.net/">Freemarker</a></li>
						<li>Turbine doesn't provide a good module initialization scheme</li>
						<li>Huge release cycles</li>
					</ul>
					Maybe,  I'm giving the impression that I don't like Turbine, but I started to learn about
					frameworks using Turbine and developed more than 10 web applications using it and it's 
					mailing list support. Thanks very, very much !
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Features">
				<p>
					Guara tries to be as simple as possible. At it's core, the framework comprises :
					<ul>
						<li>A <a href="components/pipelineManager.html">Pipeline Manager</a></li>
						<li>An Avalon container implementation called 
							<a href="components/pulga.html">Pulga</a></li>
						<li>Some valves, modules,templates and simple 
							<a href="components/index.html">components</a></li>
					</ul>
					Guara fulfills all user request executing a selected <a href="#">Pipeline</a>. <br/>
					This enables Guara to be particularly proper to 
						<a href="ajax-integration.html">ajax integration</a> maximizing code reuse.
				</p>
      		</subsection>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>